# **JULIA LARISSA GEISLER**

JULIALARISSA.COM | JULIA@JULIALARISSA.COM | +1 (802) 598-0755

#### **SELECTED PROJECTS**

# Information Architecture: Chase Hospitality Website

Articulating the Information Architecture problem, usability testing, open card sorting, and prototyping to redesign the hospitality group's website and illustrate a new user flow with rationale.

#### UX Research Report: Wearables for Motivation

User research focused on aspects wearables may be lacking as fitness motivation tools. Synthesizing results and recommending design changes in an ACM-formatted report.

# Service Design: Telus Health App LifeJourney

Working with Telus to present omni-channel integrations in a Service Design Blueprint for their tele-health app by researching, conducting participatory design workshops, and synthesizing findings.

### **SKILLS**

Advanced Adobe InDesign, Adobe Photoshop, Microsoft 365 Suite, Figma, Intermediate Adobe Illustrator, Sketch, HTML/CSS, Balsamiq, Mural, Jira, Mac OS, Windows.

User research, storyboarding, wireframing, prototyping, information architecture, typography, journey mapping, usability testing, design thinking, WCAG, Agile/Scrum.

# **EDUCATION**

# Master of Information (MI) September 2020 - May 2022 University of Toronto, Faculty of Information (Canada)

Program: User Experience Design, 3.93 GPA

- · VP Communications: Master of Information Student Council (2021-2022)
- · First Year Professional Development Committee Co-Chair: Master of Information Student Council (2020 2021)

# Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA) September 2012 - May 2016 Pace University, Lubin School of Business (New York, NY)

Major: Advertising & Integrated Marketing Communications, Cum Laude

- · Universität Mannheim: Semester Study Abroad
- · Creative Director: Pace University Brand Marketing Team for the American Advertising Federation's National Student Advertising Competition

# German School July 2014 - August 2014 Middlebury College Language Schools (Middlebury, VT)

7-Week Intensive Immersion Program

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Richemont Americas (Shelton, CT)

June 2021 - Ongoing

**UX Design Intern,** Recipient of Richemont Summer Internship Agility Award Crafting a user-friendly digital employee experience across all departments and brands by:

- Optimizing and digitizing workflows/redesigning existing sites or flows by gathering requirements, user researching using generative and evaluative methods, and designing mock-ups in Figma.
- Presenting solutions to stakeholders in understandable terms by developing personas, creating support documents, and providing reasoning for decisions backed by research.
- $\cdot$  Organizing intranets and knowledge bases by advising on best practices for information architecture.
- Encouraging a UX-centric environment by promoting a Champions program.

# Vinous Media (New York, NY) February 2017 - July 2020 Publishing & Operations Manager, Operations Assistant

- Translating user feedback from customer service reports into prototypes while liaising with developers on feasibility and prioritization.
- Managed all publishing operations by formatting and proofreading articles with up to 600+ wine notes, editing photos, and sending email campaigns.

# Valentina Kova (New York, NY) Assistant to Director, Intern

January 2015 - September 2016

- · Managed design projects including lookbooks, press kits, and event invitations.
- · Assisted with events, client relations, public relations, and bookkeeping.